### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER & WEB DEVELOPER**

## KATHRYN SHERAZI

## **PROFILE**

Kathryn's skills as a designer have evolved over the last ten years, mainly focusing on website design and development, and digital marketing. She has primarily worked as an independent, in-house designer in a team environment. Through experience, Kathryn has developed fantastic project management skills, and an acumen for positively analyzing the teams' work product and improving effectiveness by introducing best practices. Her favorite part of being a designer is working step by step through a project, seeing it come to fruition, and performing to get the project's desired results. Kathryn is seeking a role where she can continue applying her design skills while working as a full-stack web developer,

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## LEAD GRAPHIC & WEB DESIGNER- JDM DESIGNS INC., MAGNOLIA, TEXAS

### **DECEMBER 2019- JULY 2020**

- Re-designed company's main website, and prefabricated signs e-commerce site.
- Catalogued prefabricated signs and uploaded data to the e-commerce platform.
- Updated branding for digital application.
- Catalogued 40 years of company's installed signage photography to streamline marketing practices.
- Developed concept and illustrated signage to scale and detailed materials for fabrication.
- Designed the company's first illuminated door unit plaque concept, which has been fabricated in mass quantity for a high-end apartment complex in downtown Houston.
- Reviewed property site plans, developed code of symbols for sign package, and marked location for installation of all signs on the property to promote efficiency for the installation team.
- Designed complete sign packages for both residential and commercial properties following ADA compliance guidelines.
- Proposed, designed, and implemented a new concept for the company's standard presentation booklet.
- · Attended weekly meetings with the art director to discuss projects and weekly goals for the design team.
- Supervised, trained, and executed design timeline with design department staff.
- Worked closely with the print department and fabrication team to notate and prepare designs for pre-press to improve production phase efficiency.
- Attended client meetings to obtain floor plans, discuss desired design outcomes, gather measurements for signage, review design work and printed signage samples, and inspect installed signage.
- Photographed and processed images of installed final products.

#### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER & ONLINE MEDIA CONSULTANT- SELF EMPLOYED**

#### AUGUST 2015- PRESENT

- Obtained clients through everyday networking opportunities.
- Established schedule for the design project and client meetings.
- Held educational sessions with clients on best practices related to design and online marketing.
- Created concept sketches based on clients' end goals, color choices, and vernacular of the project.

- Established and implemented branding guidelines for print and online media
- Produced websites that promote SEO best practices, and provided clients accessibility in increasing their optimization.
- Executed designs to all channels of online marketing.
- Designed print materials with preexisting client branding.
- Met with printers, reviewed files, produced pre-press files, and managed printing and distribution of materials for clients.

## LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER & DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST- BETTERHOMES REAL ESTATE, DOHA, QATAR AUGUST 2015- AUGUST 2016

- Received branding guidelines from head office design team and implemented best practices through all local design collateral.
- Managed the development and continuous improvement of companies' websites.
- Developed social media campaigns to increase organic interaction and brand awareness.
- Developed and managed direct marketing campaigns.
- Reviewed company policies and systems to design forms and informative brochures to assist the sales team.
- Captured and processed all photography for property promotion.
- · Assessed marketing needs, then prepared, proposed, and implemented marketing campaigns for landlords and developers.
- Conducted market research required to design and establish effective marketing strategies.
- Prepared proposals promoting companies' services.
- Prepared monthly external reports for clients and internal reporters for company manager.

# LEAD GRAPHIC DESIGNER & MARKETING SPECIALIST- COREO REAL ESTATE & AFFILIATED COMPANIES, DOHA, QATAR MAY 2012- OCTOBER 2014

- Established and implemented branding guidelines for print and online media, vehicle branding, and packaging use.
- Managed the development and continuous improvement of companies' websites.
- Managed social media accounts to increase organic interaction and brand awareness.
- Developed and managed direct marketing campaigns.
- Supervised personnel preparing monthly newsletters and surveys.
- Trained and supervised company interns.
- Designed and distributed advertisements, newsletters, and invitations for all events.
- Designed, coordinated fabrication, and supervised the assembly of company booths for conferences.
- Wrote, designed, and managed the printing of all materials for distribution at company events and conferences.
- Represented company at all conferences and marketing events to network with targeted clientele and partnership development.
- Assisted law staff with presentation preparation for a lecture series; also attended lectures to provide additional support.
- Captured and processed all photography for company-related events, conferences, and lectures.
- · Provided imagery, supervised layout, and designed advertisements for both local and international publications.
- Developed and launched the first 360° virtual tours used by a real estate company in Qatar.
- Assessed marketing needs, then prepared, proposed, and implemented marketing campaigns and brand development for properties in The Pearl, Qatar.
- Conducted market research required to design and establish effective marketing strategies.
- Prepared proposals promoting companies' services.

• Prepared monthly external reports for clients and internal reports for clients

## GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERN- CAPE FEAR PUBLISHING, RICHMOND, VIRGINIA

#### JUNE 2010- JULY 2010

- Reported and worked directly under the Art Director on the August 2010 issue of Virginia Living Magazine.
- Reviewed, catalogued, and edited images to be used in the company's magazines.
- Designed layouts for several spreads for the August 2010 issue
- Accompanied Art Director in gathering imagery to be used in spread layouts.
- Accompanied Art Director to press checks during production.

## **EDUCATION**

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER CERTIFICATION- THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN (CPE) HOUSTON, TEXAS JUNE 2020- ONGOING

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS GRAPHIC DESIGN- VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY RICHMOND, VIRGINIA MAY 2010- MAY 2011

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS GRAPHIC DESIGN- VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY DOHA, QATAR AUGUST 2007- MAY 2010

## **SKILLS**

- WEBSITE DESIGN
- FRONT-END (UI) WEBSITE DEVELOPMENT- HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT
- SOCIAL MEDIA- CAMPAIGN PLANNING, DESIGN, AND EXECUTION
- GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- MARKETING AUTOMATION PLATFORMS
- EMAIL MARKETING SERVICES
- ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE
- BRANDING & SYSTEM WORK- DESIGN, DEVELOPMENT, AND APPLICATION
- VIDEO AND PHOTOGRAPHY EDITING

## **CONFERENCES AND LECTURES**

DANDAPANI CORPORATE WELLNESS 'WORK LIFE BALANCE' LECTURE DOHA, QATAR 2014

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR TASMEEM 'SYNAPSE' DOHA, QATAR 2011

NANCY SKOLOS AND TOM WEDELL LECTURE RICHMOND, VIRGINIA 2011

PROJECT M LECTURE RICHMOND, VIRGINIA 2010

DRESS CODE (GRAPHIC DESIGN FIRM) LECTURE RICHMOND, VIRGINIA 2010

MIRCO ILLIC DESIGN OF DESCENT LECTURE DOHA, QATAR 2010

MILTON GLASER WORKSHOP & LECTURE DOHA, QATAR 2010

ISLAMIC ART SYMPOSIUM 'DIVERSE ARE EIR HUES' DOHA, QATAR 2009

MOUSHARAKA: ICOGRADA DESIGN WEEK IN QATAR DOHA, QATAR 2009

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR TASMEEM DOHA, QATAR 2008

### **AWARDS & HONORS**

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY- CULTURAL EXCHANGE SCHOLARSHIP RICHMOND, VIRGINIA 2010

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR- VCU QATAR SUMMER SCHOLARSHIP DOHA, QATAR 2008

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR- THE VCU QATAR RECOGNITION AWARD DOHA, QATAR 2008

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR- DEAN'S LIST FALL DOHA, QATAR 2007

## **EXTRACURRICULAR**

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR- STUDENT EXCHANGE PROGRAM RICHMOND, VIRGINIA 2010 - 2011

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR - GRAPHIC DESIGN INTERNATIONAL FIELD STUD PROGRAM KUALA LUMPUR, MALAYSIA 2009

VIRGINIA COMMONWEALTH UNIVERSITY IN QATAR- PREPRESS FIELD STUDY PROGRAM BEIRUT, LEBANON 2009

#### **REFFERENCES**

SAM YOUSSEF- MANAGING DIRECTOR BETTERHOMES REAL ESTATE QATAR- SAM@BHOMESQATAR.COM

PETE HANSEN- OWNER OF TWOHANSENS (FREELANCE CLIENT I HELD CONSULTING SESSION WITH)- PETE.PAH@ME.COM

TIM JANAK- MENTOR & FRIEND (RELATED TO MY PERSONAL MASSAGE BUSINESS) +1(832) 767 - 8549

### **HOBBIES**

YOGA, HEALTH, AND WELLNESS